Guide to the Building Reference Collection, 1972 - 2004 UA.01.11.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Building Reference collection
1972 - 2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0005
3.5 Linear Feet
The Building Reference Collection contains files of clippings, publications, specifications, and other materials about the Duke University campus, including dormitories, classroom buildings, gymnasiums, stadiums, facilities, statues, and landmarks. Some files include information about the people after whom particular buildings were named. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. English.
4,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Building Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Related Material
Horace Trumbauer Architectural Drawings.
University Archives, Duke University.
Frank C. Brown Papers.
University Archives, Duke University.
Operations and Maintenance Dept. Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Sarah P. Duke Gardens Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Campus planning -- North Carolina -- Durham; College buildings -- Planning; Clippings (information artifacts); Duke University. University Archives; Duke University -- History; Duke University -- Buildings
- Cross references (Box 1)
- Ackland Art Museum (Proposed) (Box 1)
- Aims of Duke University. Plaque (Box 1)
- Allen Building (Box 1)
- Alspaugh House (Box 1)
- Alumni House (Box 1)
- Anderson House (Box 1)
- Aquatic Center (Box 1)
- Architects (Box 1)
- Architecture: "Duke by Design" / David W. Dunlap (Box 1)
- Architecture of Duke University, Clippings (Box 1)
- Architecture of Duke University, 2 folders (Box 1)
- The Ark (East Campus) (Box 1)
- Art Building (East Campus) (Box 1)
- Art Museum (formerly Science Building) (Box 1)
- Arts Complex (tobacco warehouse) (Box 1)
- Asbury Building (East Campus) (Box 1)
- Athletic Facilities (map) (Box 1)
- Aycock House (Box 1)
- Baldwin Auditorium (Box 1)
- Bells (Box 1)
- Benches (residence halls) (Box 1)
- Benjamin Duke Mansion, 109 Fifth Avenue, NYC (Box 1)
- Biddle Music Building (Box 1)
- Biological Sciences Building (Box 1)
- Bishop's House (formerly Infirmary) (Box 1)
- Bivins Building (Box 1)
- Blacknall House (Box 1)
- Blueprints (Box 1)
- Branson Building (Box 1)
- Keith and Brenda Brodie Recreation Center (East Campus) (Box 1)
- Browning Family Cemetery (Box 1)
- Bryan University Center, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Bryan University Center. Dedication (Box 1)
- Joseph and Kathleen Bryan Research Building (Box 1)
- Cameron Indoor Stadium (Box 1)
- Cameron Annex. See: Schwartz-Butters (Box 1)
- Campus Drive Bridge (Box 2)
- Campus Planning (map) (Box 2)
- Card Gym (also Aquatic Center) (Box 2)
- Carillon (Box 2)
- Duke Center for Living (Box 2)
- Central Campus Apartments (Box 2)
- Chapel
  - B. H. Duke Memorial (Flentrop Organ) (Box 2)
  - Crypt (Box 2)
  - Dacus Plaque (Box 2)
  - Dedication Programs (Box 2)
  - Design and Construction (Box 2)
  - Early History (Box 2)
  - Memorial Chapel - Duke Family Memorial and Brombaugh Organ (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 2)
  - Organ (Box 2)
- CIEMAS (Center for Interdisciplinary Engineering, Medicine and Applied Sciences Building) (Box 2)
- Classroom Building (formerly Carr Building) (Box 2)
- Clock Tower. West Campus (Box 2)
- Construction (Box 2)
- Construction. Cost (Box 2)
- Construction. History / Chronology (Box 2)
- Coombs Field (Box 2)
- Cornerstone. West Campus, Duke University (Box 2)
- Crowell Science Building (formerly Pan-Hellenic House) (Box 2)
- Crum and Forster Building. 705 Broad Street (Box 2)
- Descendents of those persons for whom buildings on the Duke University Campuses have been named (Box 2)
- Development Office (Box 2)
- Divinity School (Box 2)
- "Doris" [James B. Duke's private railroad car] (Box 2)
- Dormitories (Box 2)
- Dormitories. East Campus, 1927 (Box 2)
- Dormitories. East Campus. Plans (Box 2)
- Dormitories. West Campus. (Box 2)
- Dormitory, Proposed. Towerview Drive (1977) and others (Box 2)
- Duke Athletic Center (Box 2)
- Duke (family) Homes / Properties (Box 2)
- Duke Homestead (Box 2)
- Duke Hotel. See: Washington Duke Inn (Box 2)
- Duke Memorial Church (Box 2)
- Duke University. General (Box 2)
- Duke University. General. Clippings (Box 2)
- Duke University. General. Description, ca. 1935-1940 (Box 2)
- Duke University. General. Studies and Published Material (Box 3)
- East and West Campuses. Map (Box 3)
- East Campus Center (Box 3)
- East Campus. General (Box 3)
- East Campus Gymnasium (formerly Alumni Memorial Gym) (Box 3)
- East Campus Heating Plant (Box 3)
- East Campus Infirmary (Advising Center) (Box 3)
- East Campus Planning Study (Box 3)
- East Campus Wall (Box 3)
- East Duke Building (Box 3)
- Edens Residence Halls (Box 3)
- Engineering School (Box 3)
- Engineering School. Nello L. Teer Engineering Library (Box 3)
- Epworth Inn (East Campus) (Box 3)
- Erwin Mill (Box 3)
- Erwin Road (Box 3)
- Faculty Commons (Box 3)
- Faculty Houses on Campus Drive (formerly Myrtle Dr.) (Box 3)
- Faculty Housing (Box 3)
- Faculty Row (Box 3)
- Falcone-Arena House (Newman Center) (Box 3)
- Finch-Yeager Building (Box 3)
- Flowers Drive (Box 3)
- Flowers Student Activities Building (Box 3)
- Free-Electron Laser Laboratory (FEL). Physics (Box 3)
- Freeman Center for Jewish Life (Box 3)
- Four Acres (B. N. Duke Home) (Box 3)
- French Family Science Center (Box 3)
- Fuqua School of Business (Box 3)
- Gazebo (Trinity, N. C.) (Box 3)
- Gilbert-Addoms Dorm (Box 3)
- Genomics Buildings (Center for Models of Human Disease. Center for Human Genetics) (Box 3)
- Golf Course (Box 3)
- Greenhouses (Botany, Bio-Sci) (Box 3)
- Gross Chemical Laboratory (Box 3)
- Hanes Field (Box 3)
- Hanes House and Annex (Box 3)
- Hart House (Box 3)
- Historical Marker, N. C. Highway. Main Street, entrance to East Campus (Box 3)
- Home Sites. Duke University (Box 3)
- Jarvis Hall (Box 3)
- John Hope Franklin Center (Box 3)
- Edwin L. Jones Cancer Research Building (Box 3)
- Jordan Building (Box 4)
- Karsh Alumni and Visitors Center, 2019 (Box 4)
- Koskinen Stadium (soccer and lacrosse) (Box 4)
- Kryzewskiville / K-ville (Box 4)
- Lamp Post (Craven Hall and Art Museum) (Box 4)
- Land (Box 4)
- Lanier Hall (Box 4)
- Law School
  - Building (Box 4)
  - Goodson Library & Star Commons Dedication, 2008 (Box 4)
- Leads and Angles, Slants and Features (Campus Handbook 1947) (Box 4)
- Lenox Baker Children's Hospital (Box 4)
- Science Research Center (Levine) (Box 4)
- Library. East Campus (Lilly) (Box 4)
- Library. Perkins
  - General (Box 4)
  - Handbooks (Box 4)
  - Rare Book Rooms (Box 4)
- Library Service Center (Box 4)
- Log Cabins (Law and Medicine) (Box 4)
- Lyndhurst House (Center for Documentary Studies) (Box 4)
- Marine Laboratory (incl. R/V Eastward) (Box 4)
- Mary Duke Building (Box 4)
- Medical Center
  - Joseph and Kathleen Bryan Research Building (Box 4)
  - Chapel (Box 4)
  - McGovern-Davison Children's Health Center (Box 4)
  - Clinical and Research Laboratory Building (Box 4)
  - Davison Building (Box 4)
  - Dialysis Center (Box 4)
  - Duke South/Duke Clinic (Box 4)
  - Eye Center (Wadsworth Building) (Box 4)
  - F. G. Hall Environmental Laboratory (Box 4)
  - General construction, renovations, etc. (Box 4)
  - Jones Cancer Research Building (Box 4)
  - Morris Clinical Cancer Research Building (Box 4)
  - Mudd Building (Library) (Box 4)
  - Nanaline H. Duke Medical Sciences Building (Box 4)
  - North Hospital (Box 4)
  - Nuclear Magnetic Resonance System (Box 5)
  - Parking Garage (Box 5)
  - Pickens (Box 5)
  - PRT (Box 5)
  - Rankin Clinical Research Unit (Box 5)
  - Sands Building (Box 5)
  - Searle Center (Box 5)
  - Stead Research Building (Box 5)
  - Woodhall Building (Box 5)
  - YMCA Building (Box 5)
- Medical School. Dedication (Davison) (Box 5)
- Medical Science Research Building (Box 5)
- Mordecai Cottage (Box 5)
- Morreene Road. Origin of the Name (Box 5)
- William D. Murray Building (Box 5)
- Names of buildings, general accounts (East and West) (Box 5)
- Nasher Museum of Art (Box 5)
- Old Chem (West Campus) (Box 5)
- Olmsted Brothers, Landscape Architects (Box 5)
- Oregon Street Complex. Kudzu Tavern. Devil's Den (Box 5)
- Page Auditorium (Box 5)
- Pegram House (Faculty Row 1892) (Box 5)
- Physics Building (Box 5)
- Phytotron (SEPEL) (Box 5)
- President's House (Duke Forest), also known as Knight House (Box 5)
- President's House (Other) (Box 5)
- Primate Center (Box 5)
- Property Owned by Duke University (Box 5)
- Property Plats (Box 5)
- Proposed Buildings (Box 5)
- Quarry (Duke; Hillsborough) (Box 5)
- Recreational Facilities. Planning, 1994 - (Box 5)
- Rigsbee Cemetery (Box 5)
- Ronald McDonald House (Box 5)
- Anne Roney Fountain (Box 5)
- Schaefer House (Box 5)
- Schwartz-Butters Athletic Center (Cameron Annex) (Box 5)
- Sheffield Tennis Center (Box 5)
- Smith Warehouse. Buchanan Blvd. (FMD) (Box 5)
- Sociology - Psychology Building (Box 5)
- Southgate Hall (Box 5)
- Stagg Pavilion (East Campus) (Box 5)
- Statues / Sculptures
  - Athletics Facilities (Butters, Coombs, Wade...) (Box 5)
  - "Nature and the Scientist." (Camel) (Box 5)
  - Benjamin Newton Duke (East Campus) (Box 5)
  - James B. Duke (West Campus) (Box 5)
  - Search for Idnentity, Teer Building (Box 5)
  - The Sower (East Campus) (Box 5)
  - Washington Duke (East Campus) (Box 5)
  - Outdoor Sculptures (Box 5)
  - Stonecarving and stonecarvers (Box 5)
- Streets, Roads, Entrances (Box 5)
- Student "Hang-outs" (Box 5)
- Terry Sanford Institute of Public Policy (Box 6)
- Trent Drive Hall (Formerly Men's Graduate Center and Graduate Center) (Box 6)
- TUNL (Triangle Universities Nuclear Laboratory) (Box 6)
- Trinity College
  - General (Pre-1924) (Box 6)
  - Randolph County (Box 6)
- Trinity Heights Historic District (Box 6)
- Trinity Park School (Box 6)
- Tunnels (Box 6)
- Turner House (Trinity Park Boarding House) (Box 6)
- Union (East Campus) (Box 6)
- Union Building (Box 6)
- University House (B. N. Duke estate) (Box 6)
- Vivarium (Box 6)
- Wallace Wade Stadium (Box 6)
- Wannamaker Dormitory (Box 6)
- War Memorials
  - Duke Chapel Memorial Quadrangle (Box 6)
  - 65th General Hospital (Box 6)
  - World War II Memorial. Dedication (Box 6)
- Washington Duke Building (East Campus) (Box 6)
- Washington Duke Inn (Box 6)
- West Campus. Seals and Shields (Box 6)
- West Duke Building (Box 6)
- West -Edens Link (Dorm) (Box 6)
- White Lecture Hall (Box 6)
- Wilson-Thornhill Recreation Center (Box 6)
- Yoh Football Building (Box 6)
- York Dining Hall (T. P. School) (Box 6)